Susan Edwards, M.D.

Tel: 212.222.2222

123 Main Place, New York, NY 10001

BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT / CLINICAL EXPERTISE / PRODUCT COMMERCIALIZATION

New Business Leadership and Clinical Expertise Improving Hospital Productivity and Performance Strategic Market Penetration / Technology Procurement / New Product Launches / Go-to-Market Programs

Clinical Expertise & Oversight

Business & Technology Advancements

Recognized for the ability to contribute thought leadership to the development of innovative clinical systems, enabling the delivery of highly effective patient care. Translates requirements into specifications for systems and integrates knowledge with research.

Led the development and deployment of solutions that cluster information in disease and episodic categories for benchmarking clinical severity and variance analysis. Trained medical professionals in advanced life saving protocols and techniques.

Email: susan@susan.com

Leading Strategist and Innovator in Large –Scale Initiatives

- Led the development of strategies in connection with information technology planning, management, and integration into clinical information systems, including a computerized physician order entry and clinical analytical databases to facilitate performance improvement and outcomes management.
- Championed the design, implementation, and ongoing improvements to operations support systems of clinical and administrative information solutions. Collaborated with technology staff to ensure clinical requirements were integrated into new systems.
- Advocated for the adoption of innovative systems and processes to support infrastructure, medical informatics concepts, experience, and knowledge were integrated with clinical and business needs.

VALUE DRIVERS

Clinical &
Administrative
Leadership
Project Management
Technical &
Business Solutions

Articulate leader well versed in developing strategic roadmaps in collaboration with senior leadership to develop, plan, and implement innovative solutions to exceed levels of patient care and management. Serve as a subject matter expert regarding medical informatics trends, experiences and approaches. Utilizes physician advisory groups to explore innovations in clinical systems to support excellence in advancements in research and patient management. Generates consensus for the practical application of new ideas and best practices.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Director, Commercial and Business Development • 2004 to Present OVERHILL DEPARTMENT OF ANESTHESIA, PERIOPERATIVE INFORMATICS, New York, NY

Key Challenge: Recruit business and technology partners for software enhancement and redesign efforts. Successfully commercialize system for use within the hospital network.

- Commercialized Overhill Perioperative Information Management System (VPIMS / Vigilance) software to Company in Birmingham, Alabama.
 - Successfully identified and secured \$2.5 million in external funding for the Company start-up venture.
 - Realized \$1.2 million in lost and underbilled services subsequent to the system's implementation. Instituted 'operative reminders', including preoperative antibiotics, which reduced surgical site infections by 50%+.
 - Identified and recruited partners to facilitate targeted and effective software enhancements and updates to meet the needs of a dynamic hospital environment. Dashboard provided real-time schedule, OR and PT status.
 - Created a sales pipeline and marketing strategy, which facilitated the adoption of and implementation of the system at ABC University Hospital, ABC Children's Hospital, DEF Surgery Center, Five Oaks Surgery Center, Wellness / Spring Hospital, and Hot Springs Surgery Center.



Associate Director, Sponsored Clinical Research, Department of Anesthesia • 2007 to Present ABC DEPARTMENT OF ANESTHESIA, PERIOPERATIVE INFORMATICS, New York, NY

Key Challenge: To utilize academic talent and professional resources in IT, patient safety, and research resources to form a business model for R&D. Work to form integrity driven partnerships between academics and industry of each.

- Performed clinical drug trials, device trials, and intellectual property work.
 - Established a contract with Korea Company for advanced development of algorithmic 'smart alerts' for real time
 patient monitoring. Performed a phased research project with capital valued at \$500,000+ and IP sharing for
 advanced monitoring.
 - Spearheaded a joint research project with AOI Microsoft on the development of a computerized Sepsis
 monitoring program for patients throughout the hospital. Transitioned from first phase with published results to
 second phased distribution to other patient populations.
 - Created architecture and data distribution format to coordinate information sharing with six hospital systems and IT groups.
 - Successfully generated funding from DEF and other institutions to create a perioperative database as part of creating a regional example of medical records sharing.

Finance Director, Board Member, Founder • 2004 to Present ADR INCORPORATED, New York, NY

Key Challenge: Develop technology of Anesthetic Gas Reclamation in real time, and obtain US and international patents.

- Founded company utilizing patented new technology to reduce environmental impact of hospital and outpatient anesthesia. Designed the system to integrate with hospital waste gas system. Built business and marketing models, forecasted revenues from initial sales, reclaimed anesthetic gasses, and potential carbon credit exchange revenue in Europe and the US. Devised market entry strategies.
 - Added value as part of building a patented valve for installation on anesthesia machines, the condensation reclamation system. Obtained FDA approval for the valve and led a Phase I clinical trial at Company.
 - Created detailed business start-up plan and leveraged strategic alliances to raise investment capital. Bootstrapped
 the company on private capital funding, and negotiated an ownership percentage with OPERON of South Korea
 to produce the condenser. Received coverage on Fox News and in the *Magazine and Alumni* magazine.

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Medical Director • 2004 to Present LIFEGUARD AMBULANCE SERVICES, New York, NY

Provided medical direction to paramedics in compliance with state mandated protocols. Directed training efforts.

Medical Director, Tactical Physician • 1998 to Present GOTHAM CITY FIRE DEPARTMENT

Directed offline medical control and trained the municipal fire department in medical techniques. Conducted annual certification classes supported by didactic tests and skill stations. Trained paramedics in advanced life saving techniques.

Medical Director, Tactical Physician • 1998 to Present GOTHAM POLICE DEPARTMENT SPECIAL RESPONSE TEAM

Created first integrated medical support within a police department's special operations unit. Trained medical personnel in advanced skills and N, B, C, detection and treatment modalities. Oversaw the integration of medics into the SRT teams.

 $\textbf{Assistant Professor,} \ Department \ of \ An esthesiology \bullet Gotham \ University \ Medical \ Center \ (2004-Present)$

Vice Chairman of the Board, Gotham Chapter • National Arthritis Foundation (Present)

Board Member, Executive Advisory Board • Healthphone, Inc. (2007-Present)

Anesthesia Resident • Gotham University Medical Center (2003-2004)

Medical Director • University of Gotham, New York Hospitals, Critical Care Transport (1998-2003)



Medical Director • Gotham / Saint Peter Transport Services (1998-2003)

Emergency Services • NYU Medical Center, University of New York Hospital (1998-2003)

Orthopaedic Surgery Resident • University of New York, Gotham Hospital (1997-1998)

General Surgery Intern • University of New York, New York Hospital (1996-1997)

EDUCATION / HONORS

Medical Doctor • The University of New York School of Medicine, New York, NY (1996)
Bachelor of Science in General Management • The University of New York, College of Commerce and Business (1989)

HONORS:

Lieutenant Commander, United States Naval Reserve • United States Naval Health Professions Scholarship

Magna cum Laude • Dean's List • James B. Rodgers, Jr. Scholarship Recipient • Capstone Men / Crimson Women Scholarship • Jason's (Senior Men's Honorary) • Omicron Delta Kappa (Senior Honorary) • Beta Gamma Sigma • Order of Omega (National Greek Honorary) • Phi Kappa Phi (Senior Honorary) • Blue Key National Honorary Society

AWARDS:

Microsoft Innovation Award Recipient – 2008 HIMSS 2008 Clinical Records-Inpatient: VIGILANCE First Place ASA Scientific Exhibit, American Society of Anesthesiologists, Las Vegas, NV October 2004

Trauma Paper Award Recipient, Alabama Chapter, American College of Surgeons 1998

CERTIFICATIONS

United States Medical Licensure Examination, Step I, Step II, Step III • Basic Cardiac Life Support, Provider • Advanced Cardiac Life Support, Provider • Master Diver Scuba Certified • Open Water Diver/Instructor Certified • Night and Limited Visibility Scuba Certified Advanced • Trauma Life Support, Provider Advanced Trauma Life Support, Instructor • Pediatric Advanced Life Support, Provider • Fundamentals of Critical Care Support, Provider/Instructor • CITI-Human Subject Protection Training Program 2006 • Mixed Gas Enriched (Nitrox) Scuba Certified • Search and Rescue Scuba Certified • Stress and Rescue Scuba Certified

PUBLICATIONS / ABSTRACTS / PRESENTATIONS

Brunson, M., Edwards, S., "Transport of Critically Ill Patients: How to Avoid Pitfalls", Clinical Pulmonary Review.

Edwards, S., May, A., McGwin, G., "The April 8, 1998 Tornado: Assessment of the Region's Trauma Response and the Resulting Injuries", Trauma Award Recipient, Alabama Chapter, American College of Surgeons Annual Meeting Journal of Trauma.

Gruszecki, A., Kahler, D. Edwards, S., Smith, D. Vines, J. et al, "Utilization, Reliability, and Clinical Impact of Point-of-Care Testing during Critical Care Transport: Six Years of Experience," Clinical Chemistry, Vol. 49, No. 6, 2003.

ABSTRACTS:

Brunson, M., **Edwards, S.,** Pettis, S., Demmons, L., Kahler, D., "Air and Ground Transportation of Patients on an Intra-Aortic Balloon Pump", Presented at the Society of Critical Care Medicine Symposium, San Francisco, CA, 1999.

Barwise, John, **Edwards, S.,** Michaels, Damon, Berry, James, "Evaluation of a New Anesthetic Scavenging Interface," Presented at European Society of Anesthesiologists Meeting, Munich, Germany, May 2007, Anesthesia and Analgesia.

PRESENTATIONS:

Presenter, Principal Investigator, Patient Safety Screening Tool (Sepsis) Improving Patient Safety Using Windows Workflow; MICROSOFT HEALTHCARE EXECUTIVE FORUM, Dallas, TX; March 13-14, 2008.

Keynote Speaker, HIMSS 2008 Microsoft Internal Healthcare Division, Patient Safety Screening Tool (Sepsis), Orlando, FL; February 2008.

Keynote Speaker, NIT Critical Care Conference, Chicago, Illinois, May 2008, "24 Hour Wireless Monitoring of Patients and Implications---Early Data of TATRAC Study Model", Sponsor THE KOREAN Medical Devices.

Keynote Speaker, SEPSIS, PSST Sepsis Monitoring Software, Gartner Healthcare Summit, Miami, FL.

Keynote Speaker, HIMMS 2007, Microsoft Internal Medical Development Group, "Sepsis, Software, and Solutions."







America's #1 Online Resume Builder

With Cover Letters

- Easy-to-use, guides you through step-by-step
- Resume templates, writing samples and tips
- One-click designs for the professional look you want
- Start from scratch or upload your resume



Already have an account?











Phone and Chat Hours: 7 Days a Week 6am to midnight EST



Write a resume - in minutes

Your resume is often your first and only chance to make a great impression on an employer. Managers will scan your resume for just 10 seconds to see if you're right for the job.

That's why your resume needs to be attractive and stand out. It needs to be well-written and highlight your skills to your best advantage.

The problem is most people don't know how to write a great resume and don't have the design skills to make it look professional.

- Our Resume Builder is designed to make resume-writing fast and easy.
- We match you with the right template and, in just one click, you can choose a professional design that will help you win the job.
- Our unique Text Tuner™ allows you to choose from hundreds of expert-written examples - no more writer's block!

Get the "most impressive resume builder on the market today". There's no risk; no obligation. We're so confident that you'll love our resume builder that you can try it for FREE.

According to our partners..."the most impressive resume builder on the market today."

onTargetjobs

YAHOO! hotjobs EmploymentGuide.com

Ret-Temps Joined

Customer Reviews

Job.com

"I was completely unaware of what companies are looking for in a resume. This product helped me word and format my professional resume and the examples were extremely useful. Overall, this is a great product. I would highly recommend these services." - A. Danihels

"This resume tool is so much better than templates - just upload or enter your resume content and you get your choice of designs. It's magical! Anyone can benefit from this tool: from students to executives!" - Belinda Yanda

View more reviews >



